<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>IW 11: Wrestling with Distributed Systems</title>
    <link>https://www.cs.princeton.edu/courses/archive/spr24/cosIW11/</link>
    <description>Recent content on IW 11: Wrestling with Distributed Systems</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://www.cs.princeton.edu/courses/archive/spr24/cosIW11/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Project Ideas</title>
      <link>https://www.cs.princeton.edu/courses/archive/spr24/cosIW11/project-ideas/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2024 15:17:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.cs.princeton.edu/courses/archive/spr24/cosIW11/project-ideas/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;rsquo;s some vague project ideas, with some basic information about which paradigms are well-suited to which ideas. I&amp;rsquo;m hopeful that this helps our brainstorming!&#xA;Local-first ideas an online collaborative editor for music, art, or anything else! a ahare-alike / buy-nothing app for arranging trades a course shopper that lets you see where your friends are enrolled a social application where you can post messages and reply to threads a collaborative application for reporting sightings of scooters Serverless ideas an online service for editing images in a predictable way a recognition pipeline for identifying items in images a continuous-integration service for compiling or checking code a compression service for removing duplicates and enforcing consistent naming in a hosted storage bucket Traditional VM ideas Most applications can be a good fit for traditional VMs&amp;mdash;including all of the above!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Collaboration Policy</title>
      <link>https://www.cs.princeton.edu/courses/archive/spr24/cosIW11/collaboration-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2024 15:16:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.cs.princeton.edu/courses/archive/spr24/cosIW11/collaboration-policy/</guid>
      <description>Note that this policy is still under construction, and as such is subject to change&#xA;So, we need to talk about chatGPT. As a practitioner and professor, I find myself really torn about how to manage the challenge of modern generative LLMs in a university setting. On the one hand, I want to acknowledge the utility of chatGPT and copilot to solve previously-intractable problems, and their ubiquity in industry today. On the other hand, we&amp;rsquo;re not trying to become promp engineers here: we&amp;rsquo;re trying to become systems engineers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Funding Application</title>
      <link>https://www.cs.princeton.edu/courses/archive/spr24/cosIW11/funding-application/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2024 21:12:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.cs.princeton.edu/courses/archive/spr24/cosIW11/funding-application/</guid>
      <description>Hi all,&#xA;You should have received an email from SEAS which included instructions for how to apply for individual funding for IW seminars. This includes cloud credits, which we will explicitly need in order to finish our IW projects for this semester. As part of your homework due 2/8, I asked the class to send in (via email to me) drafts of your funding applications for SEAS funding. We&amp;rsquo;ll look at these in the latter half of class on 2/8.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Paradigm Overview</title>
      <link>https://www.cs.princeton.edu/courses/archive/spr24/cosIW11/paradigm-overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2024 21:11:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.cs.princeton.edu/courses/archive/spr24/cosIW11/paradigm-overview/</guid>
      <description>In this assignment, due February 8th, we asked the class to take three paradigms of cloud computing, and present a 15-minute talk on how to use each paradigm to write a distributed program.&#xA;Local-First programming In local-first programming, programmers are encouraged to write collaborative applications which share state via a limited number of &amp;ldquo;built-in&amp;rdquo; concurrent replicated data types (CRDTs). Each individual application is written from the perspective of a single client computer.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Homework</title>
      <link>https://www.cs.princeton.edu/courses/archive/spr24/cosIW11/homework/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 19:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.cs.princeton.edu/courses/archive/spr24/cosIW11/homework/</guid>
      <description> due: 2/8 paradigm overviews funding application draft due: 2/15 funding deadline </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Calendar</title>
      <link>https://www.cs.princeton.edu/courses/archive/spr24/cosIW11/calendar/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2024 16:49:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.cs.princeton.edu/courses/archive/spr24/cosIW11/calendar/</guid>
      <description> February Mon Tues Wednes Thurs Fri Satur Sun 1 Class 11am-12:30pm 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 homework Class 11am-12:30pm 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 Funding Deadline Class 11am-12:30pm 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 Proposal Deadline Class 11am-12:30pm 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 Class 11am-12:30pm March Mon Tues Wednes Thurs Fri Satur Sun 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 Class 11am-12:30pm 8 9 Checkpoint Form 10 11 12 13 14 Class 11am-12:30pm 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 Class 11am-12:30pm 22 23 24 25 26 How to: talk 27 28 Class 11am-12:30pm 29 30 31 April Mon Tues Wednes Thurs Fri Satur Sun 1 2 3 4 Class 11am-12:30pm 5 6 7 8 9 How to: Paper 10 11 Class 11am-12:30pm 12 13 14 Upload Presentation 15 16 17 18 Class 11am-12:30pm 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 Class 11am-12:30pm 26 27 28 Final Report 29 30 </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Posts</title>
      <link>https://www.cs.princeton.edu/courses/archive/spr24/cosIW11/posts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2024 16:34:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.cs.princeton.edu/courses/archive/spr24/cosIW11/posts/</guid>
      <description>Emails sent to the class Welcome to IW11! Funding application Let&amp;rsquo;s brainstorm! </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to Iw11</title>
      <link>https://www.cs.princeton.edu/courses/archive/spr24/cosIW11/welcome-to-iw11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2024 17:02:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.cs.princeton.edu/courses/archive/spr24/cosIW11/welcome-to-iw11/</guid>
      <description>Hello all!&#xA;(TL;DR: fill out the form and check the website for more information)&#xA;I am writing to welcome you to the Independent Work Seminar on “Wrestling with Distributed Systems&amp;quot; and to introduce myself as your independent work adviser. Welcome!&#xA;Almost every major application out there is a distributed system, even things as simple as Microsoft Word or as complicated as the stock market. You interact with distributed systems when you turn on your phone, send an email or message, buy a ticket to a concert, or do almost any basic activity as part of daily life.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
